Guide to the Sam di Bonaventura papers, 1900-1998
George Mason University Libraries
- Dr. Sam di Bonaventura papers
  - Appreciation I 1992 (Box 116)
    Contents: Notes, Articles, Class Administration Headings: 1.Calendar, 2.General Information, 3.Quiz Sample, 4.Course Topics, 5.Reading Lists, 6.Listening Lists, 7.Terminology, 8.Historical Periods, 9.Elements of Music, 10.Melodic Elements, 11.Harmony-Tonality, 12.Texture, 13.Bach:Biography, 14.Handel: Biography, 15.Vocal Forms, 16.Mass, 17.Cantata, 18.Baroque, 19.Oratorio, 20.Venice, 21.Suite, 22.Partita, 23.Chamber- Orchestral, 24.Orchestra, 25.Orchestra:Seating, 26.Orchestra:Score, 27.Orchestras/Conductors of the World, 28.String Instrument Makers, 29.Orchestra:Sound, 30.Orchestra:Show-off Pieces Dates of materials:1992
  - Appreciation II 1976 (Box 116)
    Contents: Notes, Articles Headings: 1.Romanticism, 2.Nationalism, 3.Ballet, 4.Concerto, 5.Symphony, 6.20th Century Dates of materials:1976
  - Appreciation III 1983 (Box 116)
    Contents: Lecture Notes, Articles, Scholarly Papers Dates of materials: 1983
  - Appreciation Tests I [1975-1979] (Box 116)
    Contents: Sample Tests Dates of materials: 1975-1979
  - Appreciation Tests II [1983-88] (Box 116)
    Contents: Sample Tests Dates of materials: 1983-1988
  - Appreciation I: Resource 1985 (Box 117)
    Contents: Notes, Articles Headings: 1.General:Syllabus, General Information, Record List, 2.Introduction:General, Introduction, History: Thumb-nail Sketch, Terminology, Sound, Pitch, Courts and Kings, 3.Materials: Melody Dates of materials: 1985
  - Appreciation II: Resource [1770-1775] (Box 117)
    Contents: Notes, Articles Headings: 1.Harmony, 2.Tonality, 3.Rhythm, 4.Meter, 5.Tempo, 6.Notation, 7.Dynamics/Timbre, Dates of materials: 1970-1975
  - Appreciation III: Resource [1989-1992] (Box 117)
    Contents: Notes, Articles Headings: 1.Texture, 2.Form, 3.Performance: Media, Instruments, Instruments: PIX, Strings, Woodwinds, Brass, Percussion, Instr. Misc., Orchestra: History, Orchestra: Seating, Orchestra: Sound, Orchestration, Orchestra: Display Pieces Contents: Lecture Notes, Sample Tests Dates of materials: 1989-1992
  - Appreciation IV: Resource 1976 (Box 117)
    Contents: Lecture Notes, Articles Dates of materials: 1976
  - Aspects 65-66- I [1965-66] (Box 118)
    Contents: Lecture Notes, Musical Scores Dates of materials: 1965-1966
  - Aspects 65-66- II [1965-66] (Box 118)
    Contents: Lecture Notes Dates of materials: 1965-1966
  - Aspects 65-66- III [1965-66] (Box 118)
    Contents: Lecture Notes, Musical Scores, Scholarly Papers Dates of materials: 1965-1966
  - Assignments/Tests 1965 (Box 118)
    Contents: Music Theory assignments and tests Dates of materials: 1965
  - Baltimore 1982-1983 [1982-1983] (Box 119)
    Contents: Articles about Baltimore Symphony Orchestra Dates of materials: 1982-83
  - Baltimore I [1916-1940] (Box 119)
    Contents: Articles, Notes, Concert Programs Dates of materials: 1916-1940
  - Baltimore I 1967 (Box 119)
    Contents: Articles, Concert Programs, Misc. Documents Dates of materials: 1967
  - Baltimore II [1940-1950] (Box 119)
    Contents: Notes, Articles, Concert Programs, Misc. Documents Dates of materials: 1940-1950
  - Baltimore II [1967-68] (Box 120)
    Contents: Notes, Articles, Concert Programs, Misc. Documents Dates of materials: 1967-1968
  - Baltimore III [1950-1960] (Box 120)
    Contents: Notes, Articles, Concert Programs, Misc. Documents Dates of materials: 1950-1960
  - Baltimore IV [1964-1967] (Box 120)
    Contents: Articles on Baltimore Symphony Orchestra Dates of materials: 1964-1967
  - Baltimore V [1967-68] (Box 120)
    Contents: Articles on Baltimore Symphony Orchestra Dates of materials: 1967-1968
  - Baltimore VI [1978-79] (Box 121)
    Contents: Articles on Baltimore Symphony Orchestra Dates of materials: 1978-1979
  - Bibliography I (Box 121)
    Content: Notes, Scholarly Papers Headings: 1.Introduction to Musicology, 2.Libraries Collections, 3.Catalogues, 4.Music Bibliographies, 5.Societies and Publications, 6.Musicologists, 7.Sarum Rite, 8.Dictionaries Dates of materials: ?
  - Bibliography II (Box 121)
    Content: Lecture Notes Headings: 1.Description of a Rare Book, 2.Bibliography Lecture VI Dates of materials: ?
  - Bolzano/Melk (Box 121)
    Content: Postcards of the cities of Bolzano, Italy and of Melk, Austria Headings: None- 2 sections with 7 double-sided pages total Dates of materials: 20th century images
  - Canaleto/Turner (Box 121)
    Content: Postcards by artists Giovanni Antonio [Canel] Canaletto (1679-1768) and J.M.W. Turner (1775-1851) Headings: None. Canaletto: paintings of Venice. Turner: paintings of Venice and other landscapes. Ten pages total of postcards in a 1" binder. Dates of materials: 20th cent. Reprints of 17th-19th cent. works
  - Carson/New Mexico (Box 121)
    Content: Postcards of the Loretto Chapel in Santa Fe, New Mexico, and of Christopher "Kit" Carson (1809-68) Headings: None. Six pages of postcards in a 1" binder Dates of materials: 20th cent. prints and photographs
  - Cezanne 1995 (Box 121)
    Contents: Postcards Dates of materials: 1995
  - Chamber Music (Box 122)
    Contents: Chamber [Music] 1 1996 22 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, bibliographies, listening lists, works-lists, lecture notes, photocopied scores, etc. for course in the history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: 1996 Chamber Music 2 1975-1979 22 1 item Contents: binder contains outlines, lecture notes, photocopied scores, etc. for course in history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: ca. 1975-1979 Chamber [Music] Misc. I 1966, 1974 22 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied book Ruth Halle Rowen: Early Chamber Music (New York, Columbia University Press, 1949), 178 p.; outlines, assignments, student grades, bibliographies, works-lists, lecture notes, etc. for course in history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: ca. 1966, 1974 Chamber [Music] Misc. II 22 1 item Contents: binder contains outlines, lecture notes, lists, photocopied and dittoed scores, etc. for course in history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Chamber Music, Chanson, Choral Literature (Box 123)
    Contents: Chamber Music 3 23 1 item Contents: binder contains outlines, lecture notes, photocopied scores, etc. for course in history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: ? Chamber Music 4 23 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and several photocopied scores for course in history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: ? Chamber Music 5 1974 23 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and several photocopied scores for course in history and literature of chamber music. Date(s) of materials: 1974 Chanson 1972 23 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and several photocopied or dittoed scores for course in Renaissance vocal music. Date(s) of materials: 1972. Choral Literature 1 1968 23 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, handouts, photocopied scores, student records etc. for course in choral literature. Date(s) of materials: 1968. Choral Literature 2 1968 23 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and several photocopied scores for course in choral literature. Date(s) of materials: 1968.
  - Churches, Class Notes, Class Notebook (Box 124)
    Contents: Churches 24 1 item Contents: binder contains magazine clippings and picture postcards of interiors and exteriors of churches and cathedrals in Europe. Date(s) of materials: ? Class Notes 1 1967-1974 24 1 item Contents: binder contains student records and lecture notes for courses in ancient and medieval music. Date(s) of materials: 1967-1974 Class Notes 2 1998 24 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, assignments, musical examples, and tests for "MUSIC 116" (course in intermediate music theory). Date(s) of materials: 1998. Class Notes: Music History: Baroque-Romantic [sic] 24 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for "Music 216 Form and Analysis." Date(s) of materials: ? Class Notes: Music History: Classical-Romantic [sic] 24 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in musical form and analysis. Date(s) of materials: ? Class Notebook: Ancient Medieval 1984 24 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabus, outlines, lecture notes, photocopied scores, etc. for a course in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1984
  - Class Strings, Classical (Box 125)
    Contents: Class Strings 1979 25 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabus, lecture notes, outlines, student records for course of group instruction in string instruments. Date of materials: 1979. Classical 1 1974 25 1 item Contents: binder contains class schedule, outlines, lecture notes, student records for a course in music of the classical period. Date of materials: 1974 Classical 2 1974 25 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in music of the classical period. Date of materials: 1974. Classical 3 1974 25 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in music of the classical period. Date of materials: 1974.
  - Classical (Box 126)
    Contents: Classical 4 1974 26 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in music of the classical period. Date of materials: 1974. Class[ical] 5 26 1 item Contents: binder contains miscellaneous lecture notes for courses in music of the classical period and in music appreciation. Classical 6 1980 26 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes for a course in music of the classical period. Date of materials: 1980 Classical 7 1969 26 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in music of the classical period. Date of materials: 1969.
  - Chamber Music Society of Baltimore, Concerto 1969 (Box 127)
    Contents: CMSB [Chamber Music Society of Baltimore] 1984-1985 27 1 item Contents: binder contains typescript draft of article "The Chamber Music Society of Baltimore: Champion of the Contemporary Composer" by Sam di Bonaventura and correspondence, research notes, press releases, photocopied concert programs, etc. relating to the history and activities of the Chamber Music Society of Baltimore from 1951 to 1985. Date(s) of materials: 1984-1985. Concerto 1969 IA 1966-1973 27 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, bibliographies, repertoire lists, and examinations for courses in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1966-1973. Concerto IB 27 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: ? Concerto 1969 II 1973 27 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, photocopied program notes, etc. for a course in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973.
  - Concerto (Box 128)
    Contents: Concerto 1969 III 1973 28 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, photocopied program notes, annotated photocopied scores, etc. for a course in instrumental and vocal concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973. Concerto 1966 IV 1973 28 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, annotated photocopied scores, etc. for a course in instrumental and vocal concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973. Concerto 1966 V 1973 28 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, annotated photocopied scores, and miscellaneous materials for a course in instrumental and vocal concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973. Concerto VI 28 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied liner notes for recordings of music by Purcell and A. Scarlatti and photocopied scores to works by Lully, Scarlatti, Lawes, and Baltzer. Date(s) of materials: ? Concerto VII 1970-1973 28 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for courses in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1970-1973.
  - Concerto (Box 129)
    Contents: Concerto VIII 1973 29 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied program notes, and photocopied scores for a course in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973. Concerto IX 29 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied program notes, works-lists, photocopied scores, and other materials for a course in concerto literature, including photocopied book The Solo Concerto by Engel (Cologne: Arno Volk Verlag, 1964), 88 pp. Date(s) of materials: ? Concerto X 1973 29 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines and photocopied scores for a course in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973. Concerto XI 1973 29 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied program notes and book excerpts, lecture notes and outlines, and photocopied scores for a course in concerto literature. Date(s) of materials: 1973.
  - Counterpoint, Danish Art, Dutch Art, Exams (Box 130)
    Contents: Counterpoint I 30 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course in the history and technique of polyphony and counterpoint. Date(s) of materials: ? Counterpoint II 30 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied scores and book chapters, and assignments for a course in the history and technique of polyphony and counterpoint. Date(s) of materials: ? Danish Art/Artists 30 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards depicting artwork, costume design sketches, and museums in Denmark and Sweden. Date of materials: ? Dutch Art I 30 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards reproducing Dutch and Flemish artwork (Anraadt Ruisdael). Date(s) of materials: ? Dutch 2 30 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards reproducing Dutch and Flemish artwork (Steen Witte). Date(s) of materials: ? Exams 1975-1984 30 1 item Contents: binder contains quizzes and examinations for courses in music history. Date(s) of materials: 1975-1984.
  - Festivals, Film Music, Folk Music, Frank Lloyd Wright, Edvard Grieg (Box 131)
    Contents: Festivals 1965-1968 31 1 item Contents: binder contains newspaper and magazine clippings, press releases, and photocopied programs concerning various American and European music festivals, arranged alphabetically. Date(s) of materials: 1965-1968. Film Music 1972-1973 31 1 item Contents: binder contains monthly program notes distributed to members of WTOP-TV's Cinema Club 9. Date(s) of materials: 1972-1973. Folk Music 5 31 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied program notes, lyrics, etc. for an 8-week course in folk music, primarily American folk song. Date(s) of materials: ? Frank Lloyd Wright 1984 31 1 item Contents: binder contains postcards and newspaper and magazine clippings related to architecture of Frank Lloyd Wright (1869-1959). Date(s) of materials: ca. 1984. Grieg 1992-1995 31 1 item Contents: binder contains postcards, magazine clippings, and play programs related to composer Edvard Grieg and playwright Henrik Ibsen; also depictions of "troll" figurines. Date(s) of materials: 1992-1995.
  - Grunewald, Harmony (Box 132)
    Contents: Grunewald 32 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards depicting paintings by Mathias Grunewald (c. 1475-1528) and the Unterlinden Museum in Colmar, France. Date(s) of materials: ? Harmony I (1) 1995-1996 32 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, lecture notes, outlines, assignments, tests, student grades, and photocopied book chapters for theory course, Music 115 (Harmony I). Date(s) of materials: 1995-1996. Harmony I (2) 1995-1996 32 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, assignments, tests, student grades, and photocopied book chapters for theory course, Music 115 (Harmony I). Date(s) of materials: 1995-1996. Harmony I (3) 1980, 1984 32 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabus, lecture notes and outlines, assignments and tests, and photocopied book chapters for theory course, Music 115 (Harmony I). Date(s) of materials: 1980, 1984. Harmony II (1) 1996 32 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabus, lecture notes and outlines, assignments and tests, student grades, and photocopied book chapters for theory course, Music 116 (Harmony II). Date(s) of materials: 1996.
  - Harmony, Haydn, Hillwood Museum, History Exams, History Review (Box #)
    Contents: Harmony II (2) 1996 33 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, assignments and tests, photocopied book chapters, and student grades for theory course Music 116 (Harmony II). Date(s) of materials: 1996. Haydn 33 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, outlines, and photocopied materials for a course in the life and music of Joseph Haydn (1732-1809). Date(s) of materials: ? Hillwood Museum 33 1 item Contents: binder contains brochures and color postcards of the Hillwood Museum in Washington, D.C. and its furnishings and artworks. Date(s) of materials: ? History Exams I 1966, 1968 33 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied achievement test in musical score analysis and photocopied GRE music exam. Date(s) of materials: 1966 and 1968. History Exams II 1962-1967 33 1 item Contents: binder contains general and comprehensive examinations and related notes in music history, music theory, and other musical concentrations. Date(s) of materials: 1962-1967. History Review I 1968 33 1 item Contents: binder contains outlines, notes, and photocopied scores for a series of lectures in music history. Date(s) of materials: 1968. History Review II 1965-1966 33 1 item Contents: binder contains outlines, lecture notes, and photocopied scores for a graduate review course in music history. Date(s) of materials, 1965-1966
  - HTA Class (Box 134)
    Contents: HTA I Take Home 34 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied scores to medieval and Renaissance musical compositions assigned to particular students for analysis. Date(s) of materials: ? HTA IV 1985-1995 34 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, outlines, lecture notes, works-lists, photocopied scores, etc. for courses in 20th-century music history and styles. Date(s) of materials: 1985-1995. HTA IV Class Notes 1979-1984 34 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, outlines, lecture notes, works-lists, photocopied book chapters, etc. for courses in 20th-century music history and styles. Date(s) of materials: 1979-1984. HTA IV Composers 34 1 item Contents: binder contains outlines, lecture notes, photocopied program notes and book chapters, etc. for lectures on specific composers from mid-19th century to mid-20th century. Date(s) of materials: ? HTA I Class Book 1989-1992 34 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, lecture outlines and notes, photocopied scores and program notes, and related materials for Music 335, a course in medieval and Renaissance music history. Date(s) of materials: 1989-1992.
  - HTA Class (Box 135)
    Contents: HTA I (1) 35 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, lecture outlines, and photocopied book chapters for Music 335, a course in ancient, medieval, and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: ? HTA I (2) 35 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture outlines and photocopied book chapters for a course in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: ? HTA I (3) 35 1 item Contents: binder contains photocopied book chapters and scores for a course in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: ? HTA I (Oral Reports) 1987-1995 35 1 item Contents: binder contains reports and scores submitted by students in courses in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1987-1995.
  - HTA Class, Instrumental Baroque (Box 136)
    Contents: HTA I Exams (1) 1983-1989 36 1 item Contents: binder contains tests for courses in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1983-1989. HTA I Exams (2) 1978-1982 36 1 item Contents: binder contains tests for courses in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1978-1982. HTA I Intro Book 1978-1996 36 1 item Contents: binder contains syllabi, class schedules, reading and listening lists, and lecture outlines for Music 535, a course in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1978-1996. HTA I Term Projects 1987-1993 36 1 item Contents: binder contains guidelines and photocopied scores for musical analysis projects for courses in medieval and Renaissance music. Date(s) of materials: 1987-1993. Instrumental Baroque I 1973 36 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, student grades, photocopied scores, and photocopied book chapters related to a course in Baroque instrumental music. Date(s) of materials: 1973. Instrumental Baroque II 36 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, and photocopied scores and tablatures for a course in Baroque instrumental music. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Instrumental Baroque, Instuments Postcards, Italian, Klee/Harmon Postcards, Lecture Notes (Box #)
    Contents: Instrumental Baroque III 37 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied scores, and photocopied book chapters for a course in Baroque instrumental music. Date(s) of materials: ? Instruments Postcards 37 1 item Contents: binder contains clippings and color postcards bearing photographs of string instruments. Date(s) of materials: ? Italian II 37 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards reproducing Italian Renaissance artworks. Date(s) of materials: ? Italian III 37 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards reproducing Italian Renaissance artworks. Date(s) of materials: ? Klee/Hartmann Postcards 37 1 item Contents: binder contains color postcards and magazine clippings reproducing art by Paul Klee (1879-1940) and Viktor Hartmann (1834-1873). Date(s) of materials: ? Lecture Notes Class-20th C. 37 1 item Contents: binder contains notes for lectures on court music, Romanticism, and 20th-century musical ideologies. Date(s) of materials: ?
  - Lecture, Madrigal, Matisse, Medieval (Box 138)
    Contents: Lecture (Arts Ed) 1978? 38 1 item Contents: binder contains notes for lectures on arts education advocacy and on performing arts venues in Baltimore. Date(s) of materials: ca. 1978. Madrigal I 1974 38 1 item Contents: binder contains student grades, lecture notes, photocopied scores, and photocopied articles and book chapters for a course on the Renaissance madrigal. Date(s) of materials: 1974. Madrigal II 38 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes, photocopied scores, and photocopied program notes for a course on the Renaissance madrigal. Date(s) of materials: ? Madrigal III 1974 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and photocopied scores for a course on the Renaissance madrigal. Date(s) of materials: 1974. Matisse 38 1 item Contents: binder color postcards and clippings which reproduce artworks by Henri Matisse (1869-1954). Date(s) of materials: ? Medieval I 1967-68 1967-1971 38 1 item Contents: binder contains lecture notes and outlines, works-lists, bibliographies, and photocopied book chapters and encyclopedia entries for courses in medieval music. Date(s) of materials: 1967-1971.
  - folder title (Box 139)